Guide to the Progressive Student Union records, RG0134
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Progressive Student Union records
1966-2008
1988-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Progressive Student Union
RG0134
15.5 Linear Feet 25 document boxes, 1 flat box, and 1 card file box
This collection consists of material gathered and created by the George Washington University Progressive Student Union as a function of their advocacy and campaign work. The type of material in the collection includes flyers, newsletters, correspondence, meeting agendas, newspaper articles, brochures, educational material, campaign material, and organizational records. This material dates from 1966 to 2008 with the majority of the material falling within the dates 1988-1996. Topics addressed in this collection include anti-apartheid, education reform, economics, environmentalism, feminism, human rights, international relations, labor union, LGBTQ issues, poverty, racism, sexism, and workers rights.
Biographical/Historical note
The Progressive Student Union (PSU) is a student organization at The George Washington University. The PSU was established in the 1980s as a multi-issue, social peace and justice student organization working to combat all forms of oppression. The PSU served as a coalition-building group, a direct action group, a campaign planning group, an event sponsor, and a provider of solidarity. The organization worked on a broad spectrum of social justice issues (including but not limited to racism, sexism, classism, heterosexism, ableism, homelessness, poverty, US foreign and domestic policy, environmental destruction, corporate control of the media, corporate control of educational institutions, increasing corporate power globally, exploitative labor policies, union busting, animal exploitation, censorship, free trade agreements, violence, war, and corporate globalization) with a variety of campus, community, national, and international organizations. The PSU was active in national and local movements, beginning with anti-apartheid/disinvestment campaigns in the 1980s. In the 1980s, it operated as the east coast headquarters of the Progressive Student Network (PSN), and for several years published the PSN News, the periodical newspaper of the Progressive Student Network. After the PSN declined after 1994, the PSU continued to operate as a catch-all progressive group, organizing and advocating for scores of issues, including women's reproductive rights, the power of labor unions, Native American rights, environmental sustainability, and many others. In recent years, PSU worked to end GW's contract with the Coca-Cola Company, to increase the wages and benefits of security guards in non-academic buildings and food service workers in the J Street restaurant complex, and to support the Employee Free Choice Act. The PSU was also instrumental in establishing the Socially Responsible Initiatives Commission in 2007-2008, which helps distribute resources by students designated for events or campaigns that promote social responsibility. The PSU worked and works with both local organizations such as DC Student Labor Action Project and local unions, as well as national organizations like United Students Against Sweatshops and Jobs With Justice. The Progressive Student Union is non-hierarchical organization with no elected officials; the group seeks to make decisions by consensus and operates through volunteers. (Source: Progressive Student Union website, <//studentorgs.gwu.edu/gwsolidarity>, 2006.)
Scope and Content note
This collection contains flyers, correspondence, meeting agendas, attendance lists, contact information, newspapers, newsletters, magazines, clippings, brochures, organization policy statements, photographs, financial records, petitions, notes, event plans, essays, GW forms and reports, educational material, organizational records, solicitation letters, campaign material, material from conferences, stickers, political campaign memorabilia, and fact sheets. The material dates from 1966 to 2008, with the bulk of the material dating from 1988 to 1996. These are the records of the Progression Student Union of George Washington University. This collection reflects the activities and beliefs of this organization. Topics addresses in this material include anti-apartheid, education reform, economics, environmentalism, feminism, human rights, international relations, LGBTQ issues, poverty, racism, sexism, and workers rights. These records were donated to the University Archives by a student leader of the Progressive Student Union in 2009.
The records are divided into five series: Operational Documents, Campaigns, Organizations, Periodicals, and Memorabilia. Upon donation, the contents of folders in this collection often did not correspond to the folder label. During formal archival processing duplicates were removed, and materials were moved into appropriate folders when neccessary.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Some records in Series 1 and 2 are restricted for 75 years from date of record creation.
Separated Materials note
Arrangement note
Organized into five series: Operational Documents, Campaigns, Organizations, Periodicals, and Memorabilia. The Campaigns series is organized into eleven subseries: Education/Student Issues, Environment, Foreign Countries, Human/Animal Rights, International Relations/Trade, Labor, LGBTQ Issues, Racism, War and Peace, Women's Issues, and Other Campaigns/Issues.
Where possible, series and subseries are arranged alphabetically or chronologically.
Acquisition note
These records were donated to the University Archives by a student leader of the Progressive Student Union in 2009.
Civil rights; Social reformers; Human rights; Human rights advocacy; Students -- Political activity; Labor unions; Equality; Gender and society; Anti-racism; Environmental justice; Student activities; Student movements; Social justice; George Washington University
- Operational Documents, 1987-2003; 1990-1996; Series 1; 2 Linear Feet
  Operational Documents
  The materials of this series include photographs, event flyers, information flyers, correspondence, financial records, meeting agendas, meeting attendance and contact lists, organization policies and guidelines, forms from the university, records from publications, information packets, images used on flyers, newspaper clipping, stationary, and merchandise catalogs. The material dates from 1987 to 2003, but it is predominately from 1990 to 1996. The material in this series was predominantly created by the GW Progression Student Union and relates to how they operated. It reveals individuals who were involved in this student organization and the types of activities undertaken. Rusty Stahl and Allison Robbins are two of the students whose names appear often in these records. Some letters from GW President Stephen J. Trachtenberg are within this series. Records relating to the Progressive Student Union publications, Unfiltered and Buff and Blue, are also within this series.
  The Operational Documents folders are grouped by type but are not organized into subseries. The folders generally follow this order: photos, flyers, publicity documents, correspondence, finances, agendas, contact information, and other.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Some records in this series are closed for 75 years from date of record creation.
  - Photos, Oxfam Hunger Banquet, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photos, protest near White House, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photos, GW staff, GW students, and labor reps, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photos, PSU/GWAC, 2001-2002; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photos, emergency march for womens lives, Capitol Hill, 04/2001; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photos, march to demand an end to third world debt, 04/29/2001; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - PSU stuff, from the files of Chris Halverson, 1987-1988; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cool past flyers, undated; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - PSU statements, other info, and flyers, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PSU flyers, 1988-1990; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PSU flyers, Fall 1990; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Event flyers, Spring 1990; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Original flyers, 1990-1991; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - PSU flyers, Spring 1991; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Event flyers, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Original flyers, 1991-1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - DC area PSN, 1991-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - PSU flyers, Spring 1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Event flyers, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Original flyers, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Event flyers, Fall 1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - PSU flyers, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - PSU flyers, 1993-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Original flyers, 1993-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Original flyers, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Flyers, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Flyers, 1995-1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Flyers, 1997-1998; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Event flyers, 1999-2000; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Graphics for flyers, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Information packets and fact sheets, circa 1999 - circa 2000; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Info packets and fact sheets, circa 2001 - circa 2002; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Documents, Spring 1997; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 1, Box 2, Folder 18)
  - PSU stationery, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Collection of articles, 1990-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Publicity/articles, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publicity/articles, 1993-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Publicity/articles, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - PSU history Vol 2 articles, 1991-1997; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Articles about us, 1995-1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Office keys, 1995-1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 2, Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hunger strike guidelines, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - FBI: what to do if they visit, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - How to outreach - Hatchet, news, press release, circa 1993 - circa 1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Relaxation techniques, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Organizational development, circa 1990 - circa 1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Old letters to PSU, 1989-1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Administration correspondence, 1994-2002; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondences between GW Pres. Stephen J. Trachenberg and Allison Robbins, 2002-2004; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Room confirmations, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Room confirmations, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - PSU money, pre 1991; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - PSU money, fall 1990; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - PSU money, spring 1991; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - PSU money, fall 1991 - spring 1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - PSU money, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - PSU money, 1993-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - PSU money, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Finances, 1995-1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Organizational guidelines, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - PSU computer account, 1992-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - PSU meeting notes, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Meeting agendas, 1992-1994; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Meetings, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1995-1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Meeting agendas and attendance, 1990-1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 3, Box 3, Folder 21)
  - PSU sign-up sheets, 1999-2000; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Rusty Stahl paper, 1994-1996; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PSU phone list, 1986-1990; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 5, Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PSU phone lists and attendance lists, 1990-1991; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 6, Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Contacts and attendance records, 1989-1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 7, Box 4, Folder 4)
  - PSU phone lists, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 8, Box 4, Folder 5)
  - PSU phone lists from meetings and for events, fall 1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6, Box R1, Folder 9)
  - Phone lists, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7, Box R1, Folder 10)
  - Mailing lists, 1991-1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8, Box R1, Folder 11)
  - Books/authors/speakers, 1995-1999; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Buff and Blue" papers, 1990-1992; RG0134 Series 1 (Box R1, Folder 12, Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Unfiltered operational stuff, 1996-1997; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Progressive merchandise, 1989-1999; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cookbook, 1993; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Stickers, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Misc items, 1990-1997; RG0134 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Contacts card file, undated; RG0134 Series 1 (Box SHARED Box 22, Box 27)
    Scope and Contents
    Index card files containing contact information for community and student organizations, and for speakers.
- Campaigns, 1966-2008; 1989-1996; Series 2; 5 Linear Feet
  Campaigns
  The materials of this series include event flyers, information flyers, newspaper and magazine articles, petitions, correspondences, notes, event plans, essays, background material, letters from GW officials, published GW documents, newsletters, and brochures. The material dates from 1966 to 2008, but it is predominately from 1989 to 1996. This series reflects the political and social issues that were important to the Progressive Student Union and the actions that they took in regards to these issues. Much of the material in this series related to campaigns that the Progressive Student Union was involved with at George Washington University, including recycling/green initiatives, labor disputes with cafeteria and parking staff, initiatives against sweatshop labor, work against particular industries connected to education, and demands for financial aid. Some campaigns were Washington, D.C. specific, such as community service work or anti-World Bank protests. Other campaigns were national or international in scope, including demilitarization, gay-rights, pro-choice, pro-Native American, anti-apartheid, anti-Gulf War, and pro-environment advocacy.
  This series is divided into eleven subseries based on content which are arranged in alphabetical order. The subseries are: Education/Student Issues, Environment, Foreign Countries, Human/Animal Rights, International Relations/Trade, Labor, LGBTQ Issues, Racism, War and Peace, Women's Issues, and Other Campaigns/Issues.
  The Campaigns series is organized into eleven subseries: Education/Student Issues, Environment, Foreign Countries, Human/Animal Rights, International Relations/Trade, Labor, LGBTQ Issues, Racism, War and Peace, Women's Issues, and Other Campaigns/Issues. Within some of the subseries, files are organized alphabetically by title.
  Some records in this series are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
  - Education and Student Issues, 1974-1996; 1990-1995; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1
    - Africana studies, 1991-1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Education, 1990-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Education for the people flyers, fall 1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Student Aid Forum, 1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Student Financial Aid, 1990-1995; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Trustees, 1974-1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Environment, 1985-2007; 1989-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2
    - Earth Day, 1989-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - GW Green Initiative I, 1990-1997; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - GW's green initiative II, 1991-1997; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Recycling, 1989-1997; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - US department of energy, 1990 and undated; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Environmental background and resources, 1987-2007; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Environmental, 1989-1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Pesticides, fertilizers, food safety, 1985-2001; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Save American forests, 1993-1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - UN conference on environment and development (UNCED), 1989-1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Countries, 1964-2001; 1989-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3
    - Africa, circa 1986; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Angola, circa 1986; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Egypt, 1979-1980; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - South Africa, 1864-1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - South African at GWU, 1985-1986; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Divestment Resources South Africa, 1983-1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 11, Box R1, Folder 13)
    - South Africa, background, misc stuff, 1986-1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Saudi Arabia, 01/1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Iraq, 1999-2001; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Turkey, 1979-1989; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Palestine background info, 1988-1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Israel, 1977-1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Middle East and anti-Gulf War GW stuff, 1990-1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Mid East background resources, 1988-1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Middle East peace conference and Israle-Palestine stuff, 1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Burma, 1999-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Indonesia/East Timor, 1993-1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Philippines, 1987-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Korea, 1991-1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Tibet, undated; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Northern Ireland, spring 1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Haiti, 1993-1995; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Haiti, 1993-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Haiti, 1991-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cuba, 1995-1997; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Puerto Rico, 1991-1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - El Salvador, 1987-1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - El Salvador, 1977-1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Peru, 1985-1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Central America, 1987-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Guatemala, 1987-1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nicaragua, 1979-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Panama invasion, 1990-1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Mexico, 1991-1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chiapas revolt, 1994-1995; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - School of the Americas / Latin American Solidarity, 1998-2001; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Human/Animal Rights, 1982-2000; 1989-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4
    - Free Mumia Abu Janal, 1992-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Civil rights, 1985-1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Death penalty, 1992-1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Leonard Peltier, 1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cruelty-Free, 1991-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Other Animal Rights Stuff, 1982-1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Human rights, general info/Amnesty Int'l stuff, 1987-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Political prisoners, 1990-1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 4 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - International Relation/Trade, 1977-2001; 1989-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5
    - NAFTA (we don't hafta), 1993-1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Iran hostage - contra, 1977-1991; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - World Bank / IMF, 1999-2001; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - WTO, 1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - IMF- WB A16, 1991-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - FTAA, circa 2001; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Jubilee 2000, 1999-2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - PNTR, undated; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - International affairs, 1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Labor, 1988-2007; 1989-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6
    - Adjunct faculty, circa 2006; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Killer Coke, circa 2007; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Corporate irresponsibilty, 1990-2006; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Sweatshops, 1999-2001; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 9, Box R1, Folder 14)
    - GTAAA, 1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Marriott / Local 32, 1988-1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Marriott Corp. - GW cafeterias petitions, undated; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 12, Box R1, Folder 15)
    - Follett, 2000; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Labor, 1998-2004; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Aramark / GW dining / petition, 1994-2002; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 15, Box R1, Folder 16)
    - Workers organizations, union, publications, 1991-1998; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Labor strikes, circa 1990 - circa 1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Parking workers, 1999-2004; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - PSU 2003-2004 campus workers, 1990-2004; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Campaign for labor rights, 1999; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 6 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - LGBTQ Issues, 1985-1996; 1989-1995; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7
    - Lesbian, gay and bisexual issues at GWU, 1989-1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Queer stuff, 1991-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Anti-homosexuals, 1992-1994; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Homophobia, 1988-1990; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Lesbian/gay/bi/queer, 1990-1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Gays and the military, 1985-1992; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Queer liberation, 1991-1993; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 7 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Racism, 1966-1999; 1989-1996; RG0134 Series 2 Subseries 8